♬
It's just stupid... And a smart girl like you?
(佐渡)
まったく… バカな話じゃ｡➡
♬
君のような聡明な女性が｡
I made the wrong decision.
(新見)
道に… 迷ってしまったんです｡
♬
ん？
(星名)そろそろ行きましょうか｡
♬
Let's get going.
(新見)ありがとうございました｡
♬
Thank you very much.
(真琴)先生 雪さんが
イスカンダル人だったって話…｡
♬
Doctor, is it true that Yuki is an Iscandarian?
(真琴)先生 雪さんが
イスカンダル人だったって話…｡
それこそ バカな話じゃ｡
That's even stupider.
♬
(土方)これは 彼女の思いだ｡➡
These were her thoughts...
...as she entrusted her sister with a dangerous mission.
危険な使命を 妹に託した
その思いだ｡➡
航海の途中で
お前は 真実を知るかもしれん｡
You may learn the truth during your voyage.
But do not let that sway you.
だが 迷うな｡
Until we meet again, safe travels.
無事な帰還を｡ 必ず戻ってこい｡
The salvation of all intelligent life...
(ｽﾀｰｼｬ)あまねく星々
その知的生命体の救済➡
That is the path of Iscandar...
それが
イスカンダルの進む道｡
We are already thirty-five days behind schedule.
(島)
我々は すでに 航海日程から➡
３５日の遅れを出しています｡
ですが➡
But if we use this subspace gate, we can shave off 30,000 light years.
この亜空間ゲートを
使用できれば➡
行程を 一気に ３万光年は➡
短縮することができる計算です｡
(真田)ゲートをコントロールする
システム衛星が➡
The system satellite that controls the gate is near.
その近傍にあり
これを攻略できるかどうかが➡
The question is whether we can take control of it.
鍵となるでしょう｡
(沖田十三)うむ｡
The core contains records of a race...
(真田)このコアには ゲートを
作り出した文明とは別の➡
A race, which controls the system satellite, different than that which built the gate.
システム衛星を運用していた
管理者とも言うべき➡
種族の存在も 記されていました｡
管理者？
Who controls it?
(真田)その種族の名前も
記述されています｡
It contains their name, as well.
Out with it.
(古代進)もったいぶらないで
教えてください｡
It was Garmillas.
(真田)ガミラスだよ｡
♬
I was seconds from destroying the Yamato. Why have you recalled me?
(ﾄﾞﾒﾙ)私は あと一歩で ヤマトに
とどめを刺せたのです｡➡
それを…｡
これは一体 なんの茶番ですか？
What's going on?
Early this morning, our Leader's ship was destroyed through sabotage.
(ﾋｽ)未明に 総統の
乗艦されていた艦が➡
何者かの工作で爆破された｡
Lord Desler has been assassinated.
デスラー総統が 暗殺されたのだ｡
(ﾄﾞﾒﾙ)えっ!?
Only two people knew he would be visiting Balun.
(ｷﾞﾑﾚｰ)総統のバラン視察を
把握していた高官は 二人だけ｡➡
One is Admiral Ditz, the Supreme Commander of Astrofleets.
一人は
航宙艦隊総司令 ディッツ提督｡➡
And the other is yourself.
そして もう一人は あなた｡➡
あなたを
総統暗殺の首謀者として➡
You are here because I am accusing you of plotting the Leader's assassination.
ここに告発します｡
That's crazy!
バカな！
(ｷﾞﾑﾚｰ)ディッツと共謀し➡
You and Ditz worked to assassinate the Leader and take control of the Empire, yes?
総統を亡き者にして
帝国の支配権を握ろうと➡
画策しましたね？
くだらん妄想につきあう気はない｡
I've no time for childish fantasies.
Fantasies, are they?
妄想… そうですか？
奥様も
身柄を拘束されたというのに｡
Even though your wife has been arrested?
Elisa? What has she done?
エリーサが？
妻が 一体 何をしたというのだ!?
You didn't know? She's been part of an anti-government movement.
(ｷﾞﾑﾚｰ)ご存じない？
彼女は 反政府運動に➡
加担していたのですよ｡
(ﾄﾞﾒﾙ)何かの間違いだ！
There must be some mistake!
That's what everyone says.
(ｷﾞﾑﾚｰ)皆さん そうおっしゃいます｡
(ﾄﾞﾒﾙ)くっ！
(ｷﾞﾑﾚｰ)国家の本質は 秩序です｡➡
Order is the foundation of any nation, and it must be maintained.
秩序は 守らねばならない｡
そのためには➡
For that to happen, anyone suspected of wrongdoing must be punished.
疑わしきは罰せよ…
それが鉄則です｡
There can be no exceptions.
Gimleh...
ギムレー！
ふっ｡
(ﾋｽ)評決を取る｡ 陪審の諸君｡
I shall take a vote. Gentlemen of the jury?
死刑｡
Death! Death! Death!
当軍事法廷は 全会一致で➡
By unanimous verdict, the tribunal sentences General Domel to death.
ドメル上級大将に
死刑を言い渡す｡
んん…｡
(ｾﾞｰﾘｯｸ)
ふふふっ… ふははははっ！
(ﾊﾞﾝﾃﾞﾍﾞﾙ)観艦式に向け
出港準備 完了しました｡
We're set to leave for the naval review. Has something good happened?
何か よいことでも？
Domel has been sentenced to death.
(ｾﾞｰﾘｯｸ)ドメルに 死刑判決が出た｡
(ﾊﾞﾝﾃﾞﾍﾞﾙ)
おめでとうございます 閣下｡
Congratulations, sir!
ふはははっ！
Launch the fleet. Our target is Balun!
全艦 発進せよ｡ 目標 バラン！
♬
≫(親衛隊)
早く行け｡ グズグズするな｡
Stay in line.
(親衛隊)
列を乱すな｡ とっとと歩け｡
≫(親衛隊)止まれ！
(ﾒﾙﾀﾞ)あっ｡
Stop!
(親衛隊)うわっ！
(親衛隊)くっ！
(ｴﾘｰｻ)ううっ！
(親衛隊)うわっ！
(ｴﾘｰｻ)ああっ！
あっ！
ダダダダッ！(銃声)
(一同)あぁ…｡
(親衛隊)立て｡
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ](親衛隊)逃亡を図った者は➡
Get up.
Anyone attempting to run will be shot on the spot. Understood?
その場で射殺する｡ 分かったな？
♬
Is that the one?
彼女か｡
ああ｡
Yes.
(島)あれが 亜空間ゲートか｡
(南部)死んでるように見えるけど｡
- Is that the subspace gate?
- It doesn't look functional...
(北野)ほんとに あんなんで➡
Can it really propel us tens of thousands of light years at once?
何万光年も
ワープできるんですか？
Yes.
(百合亜)できるわ｡
No way...
(佐渡)できんよ｡➡
いくら わしでも
これは お手上げじゃ｡
Even I can't do anything with it.
However, at this rate, it will affect ship functions.
(真田)しかし
このままでは 艦の運航に➡
支障を来すことになります｡
(佐渡)
艦の運航も 医者の領分なのかね？
Is maintaining the ship a doctor's duty?
It is not.
(真田)違います｡
(佐渡)んん…｡➡
それより 説明してくれんか｡➡
Anyway, explain...
Why do this? It isn't like you.
どうして こんな
らしくないことをしたんじゃ？➡
Why didn't you tell anyone?
なぜ この事実を公表せん？➡
あんたなら そうするじゃろ｡
Normally, you would have.
(真田)中央司令部の命令です｡
(佐渡)そんなこと聞いとりゃせん！
Orders from Central Command...
That isn't what I'm asking!
｢たとえ
それが命令であったとしても➡
"You need the courage to disobey an order you believe is wrong."
間違っていると思ったら
それを正す勇気も必要だ｣➡
I once told Kodai that.
そんなことを
古代に言ったことがあってな｡
We should have been honest with ourselves.
我々は
自分に正直であるべきだった｡
I will assume full responsibility for its disclosure.
これは 私の一存で開示する｡
≪シューン(ﾄﾞｱの音)
≪(岩田)森さんが➡
I'm disappointed that Mori's an alien.
≪異星人だったなんて
がっかりだよ｡
Yeah, really...
(遠山)なんだなぁ…｡ おっ！
(岩田)
俺 ファンだったんだけどな～｡➡
I was a fan!
ん？ あっ…
１００式 発艦準備 完了してます｡
The Type 100 is ready to go!
Thanks.
ご苦労｡
I'm ready.
(真田)待たせたね｡
(相原)
古代さんは 護衛だとしても➡
Even if Kodai went for protection, why would the XO take Mori?
副長は なんで
森さんまで連れてったのかな？
Maybe it's because she's an Iscandarian?
(北野)
ｲｽｶﾝﾀﾞﾙ人だからじゃないんですか？
(南部)違う！
彼女は そんなんじゃない！
That's not true! She is not!
(太田)でも スターシャさんの
ﾒｯｾｰｼﾞを持ってたんだよな｡
But she had that message from Starsha...
(北野)
1年以上前の記憶がないってのも…｡
She also has no memories from over a year ago.
Stop speculating!
(南部)臆測で 物を言うな！
(島)作戦行動中だぞ｡➡
We're in the middle of a mission. No talking.
私語を慎め｡
ピッ(ﾚｰﾀﾞｰの音)
The Type 100 has entered the system satellite.
(西条)１００式
システム衛星に入りました｡
♬
(真田)ブービートラップの類いは
なさそうだ｡
There don't appear to be any booby traps.
Looks like a long-abandoned base.
(真田)基地としては かなり前に
破棄されたものらしい｡➡
慣性質量を感じるということは➡
If the inertial mass system is on-line, the rest must still be functional.
死んでいるわけでは
なさそうだな｡➡
これは 役に立つかもしれない｡
あとで回収させよう｡
This could be useful. We'll bring it back on board later.
Let's get this done.
さっさと終わらせましょう｡
♬
はぁ… どっちに行けばいいんだか｡
(真田)うん｡
I don't know which way to go.
Yeah...
Didn't you say a civilization older than that of Garmillas made this?
(森雪)確か
このシステムは ガミラスより➡
古い文明が作ったんですよね？
(真田)そうらしい｡
So it seems.
その人たちは ガミラスに
汚されたって思うのかな｡
Do you think they'd be upset that the Garmillans have tainted it?
"The sadness of being tainted makes the snow fall once more," huh?
(真田)｢汚れちまった悲しみに
今日も小雪の降りかかる｣か｡
なんです？
中原中也ですね｡
What's that?
Chuya Nakahara.
昔 この詩が好きなヤツがいてね｡
I once knew someone who loved that poem.
確か ２０世紀の詩人ですよね｡
Wasn't he a twentieth-century poet?
A poet from over two hundred years ago?
２００年前の詩人か｡ あっ｡
Is that...
なあ それって！
な… 何？
What?
Do you think the Iscandarians knew about this Nakahara guy?
イスカンダルの人間が
その中原なんとかを➡
知ってると思う？
えっ？
そんな昔の詩人
イスカンダル人が知ってると思う？
Could the Iscandarians have known such an ancient poet?
あっ… あぁ｡
(真田)静かに！
Be quiet!
番犬は 置いてったみたいですね｡
Looks like they left guard dogs.
There may be more.
まだ いるかもしれない｡ こっちだ｡
This way.
(新見･心の声)
≪いつでも 先生は そうでした≫
He always was that way...
Whenever I didn't know what to do, he'd show me the way.
≪迷ったとき
いつも 道を示してくれた≫
Seven Years Ago - AD 2192
Here are the papers you requested.
(新見･回想)
((これ 頼まれていた資料です))
Thank you.
((ありがとう))
((ふふっ｡ 異星人の艦隊は➡
It appears that the alien fleet has reached Mars.
火星軌道近くまで
進出してきてるみたいです))
((そうらしいね))
So I hear...
The rumor is they've upgraded Inner Planet War shelters, and everyone's evacuated.
((内惑星戦争の
地下シェルターを改造して➡
みんな
そちらに避難するってうわさも))
((≪ガチャ(ﾄﾞｱの音)))
((≪(守)心配ないって))
Don't worry.
((ん？ 古代君))
Kodai?
They'll soon be starting a big operation to defend Mars.
(守)
((今度 火星を絶対防衛線とした➡
反抗作戦が始まるらしいんだ))
(新見)((どこの情報？))
(守)((ひ･み･つ！))
Where did you get that information?
It's a secret.
((はぁ～｡ で なんの御用？))
So, what do you want? You can't enter this lab without permission.
((この研究室には
許可を取らないと➡
入れないんですよ))
((薫君は 許可取ってるの？))
Do you have permission?
((私は
真田先輩に頼まれた資料を…))
I...
I'm bringing materials Sanada requested.
((ははっ))
Same here.
(守)((俺と同じだな｡ これ))
(真田)((ん？))
Here.
(守)((この前
読んでみたいって言ってただろ))
You said you'd like to read these.
A book of poems?
(新見)((詩集… ですか？))
(真田)((そうだが))
Yes...
I thought equations were his only interest.
(守)((数式にしか
興味ないと思ったろ？))
(新見)
((うん… いえ！ 違います))
Yeah.
I mean, no!
(真田)((そんなことより 古代➡
Anyway, Kodai, your friend is here.
迎えが来てるぞ))
(守)((あっ しまった！➡
That's right! I promised to meet my brother!
弟と約束してたんだ))
Bye.
((じゃあ))
He does whatever he feels like, doesn't he?
((遠慮のない人))
((あいつは 自分に正直なんだ))
He's honest with himself.
((君も 正直になった方がいい))
You could learn a thing or two from him.
♬
古代君…｡
Kodai...
Honest with yourself?
自分に正直に… か｡
でも よかった｡
I'm glad I was able to prove you're an Earthling.
君が 地球人だって証明できてさ｡
考えてみれば そうだよな｡
I mean, you have to be, right?
でも… じゃあ なんで私は
１年前からの記憶しかないの？
But then, why don't I have any memories from beyond a year ago?
Is it just a coincidence that that's when Yurisha disappeared?
ユリーシャさんが １年前から
行方不明になってるのは➡
偶然の一致なの？
Well...
それは…｡
(真田)偶然ではないよ｡➡
It is not.
君には 伝えるべきだった｡
えっ？
I should have told you.
君とユリーシャは
同じ事故に遭遇した｡➡
You and Yurisha were involved in the same accident.
Whether an accident or terrorism... No one really knows.
単なる事故か
あるいは テロだったのか➡
真相は依然 やぶの中だ｡➡
But in that incident, you lost your memory, and Yurisha went into a coma.
だが その事故で 君は記憶を➡
そして ユリーシャは
意識を失ってしまった｡➡
We did all we could, but she never woke up.
あらゆる手を尽くしたが
彼女の意識は 戻らなかった｡
Why didn't you tell us?
なんで黙ってたんです？
We still don't know where in the Large Magellanic Cloud Iscandar is.
(真田)我々は
いまだに イスカンダルが➡
大マゼランの どこにあるかを
知らない｡
えっ？
でも イスカンダルから➡
But we have the map they sent!
航路図が…｡
そうですよ｡
That's right. That data has been entered into the Automatic Navigation System.
自動航法室には そのデータが
インプットされてるんでしょ？
(真田)そんなものはない｡
(２人)えっ？
And the location doesn't exist.
彼女が イスカンダルへの道を
示してくれる… そのはずだった｡
She showed us the path to Iscandar. Or she was meant to.
えっ？ 待ってください｡
じゃあ ここまで どうやって？
Wait! But then, how could we have come this far?
彼女の記憶をたどって｡
We've followed her memories...
まさか それって…｡
You can't mean...
自動航法装置の中核は
ユリーシャなんだよ｡
Yurisha is the core of the Automatic Navigation System.
(２人)はっ！
♬
(真田)我々は
彼女の記憶をトレースして➡
We've been searching for Iscandar by tracing her memories.
イスカンダルに
向かおうとしている｡
そんな…｡
(真田)道義的に➡
But...
I know that it's ethically wrong. And we must take responsibility.
許されないことをした｡
その責は 負わねばならない｡➡
And that's why we will bring her home safely.
そして だからこそ 我々は➡
彼女を 無事に故郷へ送り届ける➡
That's part of the Yamato mission.
それも ヤマトのミｯションなんだ｡
じゃあ
あのメッセージカプセルは？
Then that message capsule...
なんで 私が…｡
Why did I have it?
Because...
(真田)それは…｡
あっ！ くっ！
バン バン バン バン！
Nice work.
(真田)さすがだな｡ では➡
Let's get inside.
そろそろ入ろうか｡
えっ？ 入るって？
Inside?
This is our goal.
(真田)ここが目的地だ｡➡
The system satellite control area.
システム衛星の制御区画だよ｡
It's open.
開きました｡
(真田)ここから先は私の仕事だ｡
The rest of this is my job.
You wait here.
君たちは ここで｡
♬
ん？ はっ！
XO Sanada! XO Sanada!
副長！ 副長！
♬
(通信)副長！
(真田)思ったとおりだ｡➡
XO Sanada!
Just as I thought.
このシステム衛星を
再起動すれば➡
If we restart the system satellite, we can open the subspace gate.
亜空間ゲートを開くことができる｡
Neutron radiation: high
えっ？ んん…｡
Do you wish to lock bulkhead D?
≪ガコン(鍵が掛かる音)
It's been locked from inside.
中から ロックされた｡
えっ？
Kodai, listen to me.
(真田･通信)古代 よく聞いてくれ｡
It appears that restarting the system will cause a massive neutron burst.
どうやら
このシステムを再起動すると➡
大量の中性子が
数秒間 放出されるようだ｡
(通信)えっ？
(通信)それじゃあ…｡
Then...
But this area is shielded.
(真田)だが この区画は
シールドされている｡ つまり➡
In other words, you'll be safe here.
(通信)
君たちは そこにいれば安全だ｡
そっちは どうなんです？
What about you?
Is it shielded?
(通信)ｼｰﾙﾄﾞされてるんですか？
されてるんですよね!?
It is, right?
What are you doing?
何やってんだ あんたは！
危険です！ やめてください！
It's dangerous! Stop!
No! Don't!
ダメだ… ダメだよ！
ドン ドン！
I'll try to undo the lock myself.
こっちで ロックを解除してみる｡
≪ドン ドン！
(通信)開けてくれ 真田さん！
Open the door, Sanada!
古代… さっき➡
Kodai, I said I had a friend who liked Chuya Nakahara's poetry, right?
中原中也の詩を 口ずさんでいた
友達がいると言ったろ？➡
That friend was Mamoru Kodai.
(通信)あれは 古代守だ｡
はっ！
Your brother, Mamoru Kodai.
(真田･通信)
お前の兄 古代守なんだ｡
You were my brother's friend?
(通信)兄さんと真田さんが友達？
ああ｡ 親友だった｡
Yes, best friends.
♬
Six Years Ago - AD 2193
If you're looking for Niimi, she's gone.
((新見君ならいないぞ))
Another meteorite. This time on Rio de Janeiro.
((例の隕石 今度は➡
リオデジャネイロに
落ちたらしい))
((明らかに
人為的に落とされている))
Clearly, they're being sent by the enemy.
((異星人は
戦術を切り替えたようだね))
The aliens have changed their strategy.
♬～
((異星人は
戦術を切り替えたようだね))
♬
((なあ たまには
外の空気を吸わないか？))
♬
Hey, want to get some air for once?
((えっ？))
♬
(守)((ひどい空だ))
The sky looks terrible.
There may be a nuclear winter.
((核の冬が来るかもしれない))
After you graduate, you're joining the Cosmo Navy?
((卒業して
そのまま 宇宙軍に入るのか？))
((ああ｡ お前は？))
Yeah, how about you?
Me... I'm not cut out for the military.
((俺は 軍には向かない人間だ))
((だが そんな自分にも
何かできることは➡
But I think there must be something I can do.
あるんじゃないか…
そう思ってる))
((お前ならできる｡ 俺には➡
You'll find something...
You'll find something I couldn't do in a million years.
逆立ちしたってできないことでも
お前にはな｡➡
A poem and an equation. Those are what we are.
詩と数式だな 俺たちは))
(真田)((ん？))
We both wish to protect this world in different ways.
(守)((道は違っても
この世界を守りたい))
In that respect, we're the same.
((その気持ちは同じってことさ))
((ふっ｡ ああ))
Yeah.
"The sadness of being defiled
((｢汚れちまった悲しみに｣))
causes snow to fall once more."
｢今日も小雪の降りかかる｣…｡
Sanada!
(通信)真田さん！
親友だっていうのに 俺は…｡
He was my friend, and I...
えっ？
I couldn't tell him that Operation M was a decoy,
(真田)俺は
メ号作戦が 陽動だってことを…➡
艦隊が おとりだったってことを➡
that the whole fleet was a decoy.
あいつに告げられなかった｡
(([ｽﾋﾟｰｶ] 作戦開始時刻は明朝０６３０))
10 Months Ago - Far East Sector Underground Dock
We will now begin loading the prototype torpedoes.
Good luck, Captain.
(石津)((では 艦長))
(([ｽﾋﾟｰｶ] 第一班➡
試製魚雷の搬入準備に入れ))
The operation begins in the morning.
(守)((いよいよ 明朝 出撃だ))
((うん))
I don't know how many ships will make it in time.
(守)((どれだけの艦が
たどりつけるか分からない))
((だが
必ず冥王星をたたいてみせる))
But we'll take out Pluto.
Did you get to see Niimi?
(真田)
((新見君には会ったのか？))
We broke up.
((別れたんだ 俺たち))
(真田)((そうか…))
I see.
I never got the chance to return this.
((長いこと
借りっぱなしだったな))
You can have it.
((やるよ｡
いや お前に持っていてほしい))
No, I'd like you to keep it.
I've read it twice, and I still don't understand why anyone likes poems.
(真田)
((繰り返し 読んでみたんだが➡
俺には 詩のよさが分からない))
((正直なヤツだな))
You don't hold back, do you?
((ははっ…))
♬
(真田)
陽動であることは 極秘だった｡➡
The fact that it was a decoy operation was top secret.
I didn't have the courage to tell my friend.
親友に 事実を告げる勇気もなく➡
I just obeyed my orders.
ただ 命令には忠実に…｡
俺は そういう男だ｡
That's the kind of man I am.
あなたから
その事実を聞かされたとしても➡
Even if he'd known, he would've gone.
兄は行ったでしょう｡
(通信)どんな状況でも
どんな理不尽な➡
No matter what the situation... No matter how unreasonable the order.
命令だったとしても
やると決めたらやり抜いちまう｡➡
If he'd decided to do it, he would.
That is how my brother was.
兄は そういうヤツだから｡
そうだな…
そういうヤツだ｡
Yes, that's the way he was.
Mamoru, your brother is following in your footsteps.
古代… 弟は
立派に お前の後を継いでいるよ｡
真田さん 俺は…
俺は 兄が詩を好きだったなんて➡
Sanada, I...
I didn't know my brother liked poetry!
知りませんでした｡
あと少し｡
Just a little more...
"The sadness of being tainted longs for nothing.
(真田)｢汚れちまった悲しみは
なにのぞむなくねがふなく➡
The sun sets helplessly with the sadness of being tainted."
汚れっちまった悲しみに➡
なすところもなく日は暮れる｣｡
Sanada, what made my brother happy?
真田さん 兄は
どんなことに笑ったんですか!?
What made him sad?
どんなことに悲しんだんですか!?
♬
Neutrons have flooded the control room.
制御室内に 中性子 発生｡
No one could have survived it.
中にいたら 生きていられない…｡
あっ！ 真田さん‼
Sanada!
♬
(百合亜)扉は開かれた｡
The door is open...
This is the path to the mother world.
これは 母なる星へと続く道｡
あっ！
♬
副長！
どこですか!? 真田さん！
XO!
Where are you, Sanada?
♬
I wanted to learn more about my brother.
俺は もっと聞きたかったんだ｡
俺の知らない 兄さんの話を…➡
あなた自身の話を｡
And more about you!
あっ 真田さん！
Sanada!
中性子は 水を通りにくいんだ｡
Neutrons don't pass through water easily.
まったく… あなたって人は…｡
You really do amaze me...
ふっ｡
ふふっ｡
♬
Chuya Nakahara Poems
Attention all crew. The gate is on-line.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ] 全艦に達する｡ ゲートは
使用できるようになった｡➡
これで ヤマトは ３万光年を➡
The Yamato will now be able to jump 30,000 light years.
跳躍することができる｡➡
だが その前に 一つだけ➡
But before we do, I must make something clear.
明らかにしなければならない
ことがある｡➡
本艦に イスカンダル人が
乗艦しているという➡
There is a rumor about an Iscandarian aboard this ship.
うわさがあるが
これは事実である｡➡
It is true.
ただし
乗組員の一人としてではない｡➡
But she is not a crew member.
She is asleep in the automatic navigation room.
彼女は
自動航法室で眠っているのだ｡
♬
You are Yurisha Iscandar?
あなたが
ユリーシャ･イスカンダル｡
No, now I am myself.
≫(百合亜)いいえ｡ 今は私｡
あっ｡
(百合亜)
私が イスカンダルのユリーシャ｡
I am Yurisha of Iscandar.
♬
Episode 17: Out of the Forest of Memory
Balun. A lighthouse in space.
The center of a network that connects the galaxy.
A gigantic enemy fleet gathers, numbering 10,000 in all.
The Yamato sets a course straight through for the Large Magellanic Cloud.
Next time: Over the Black Light.
There are 273 days left before humanity is extinct.
(ﾄﾞﾒﾙ)彼らは来る｡
必ず 七色星団を突き進んでくる｡
本艦は 七色星団を抜け
イスカンダルを目指す｡
(ﾄﾞﾒﾙ)
目標 七色星団｡ 全艦 発進せよ！
その目で
全てを見届けていただきたい｡
人類が 救うにたりうる
存在なのかどうかを｡
彼らは来た… 戦いと共に｡
(ﾃﾞｽﾗｰ)テロンの諸君
見てくれるだろうね？
山口県と島根県で記録的な豪雨と
なり、
気象庁では、大規模災害の危険が
極めて高いとして、
最大級の警戒を呼びかけている。
山口市の山間部を流れる阿武川で
す。